A Guide to the James J. Kilpatrick Papers 1959-1985
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
James J. Kilpatrick Papers 1959-1985
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6626-j,-k,-m
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the Library by James J. Kilpatrick on 6 November 1980, 15 December 1982, and 29 July 1985.
Scope and Content Information
The collection contains manuscripts of columns, and manuscripts, correspondence and related material for his books The American South: Four Seasons of the Land; The American South: Towns and Cities; The Foxes' Union; and A Political Bestiary.
The papers also contain personal correspondence, 1959-1981, correspondence with readers of his syndicated column and viewers of "Agronsky and Company"; and a videocassette recording "Vietnam War Memorial," 1982. Current domestic issues and foreign affairs are the chief topics, particularly federal bureaucracy, big business, conservation, conservatism, constitutional interpretation, crime, the economy, education, presidential elections, 1976, 1980, and 1984, energy, Equal Rights Amendment, health care, labor, laetrile, legal services, nuclear power, politics, U.S. postal service, race relations, the Supreme Court, taxation, veterans, and welfare.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by subect and chronologically under the following Series: Personal Correspondence; Reader Mail; Radio and Television Transcripts; Articles, Books, and Related Material; Miscellaneous Material; and Videocassette and Tape Recordings.
Contents List
- Personal Correspondence
  - Personal Correspondence: A-D 1977-1981, 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Personal Correspondence: Dure, Leon 1959-1962, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Personal Correspondence: Dure, Leon - his manuscript 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Personal Correspondence: E-F 1959-1981, 11 folders (Box 2)
  - Personal Correspondence: G-H 1950-1963, 1977-1981, 7 folders (Box 3)
  - Personal Correspondence: Haislip, Fred 1958-1962 (Box 3)
  - Personal Correspondence: I-M 1961-1962, 1975-1982, 10 folders (Box 4)
  - Personal Correspondence: MacNelley, Jeff 1976-1978 (Box 4)
  - Personal Correspondence: N-R 1959-1963, 1977-1981, 9 folders (Box 5)
  - Personal Correspondence: R 1977-1981 (Box 6)
  - Personal Correspondence: Robertson, A. Willis 1959-1962 (Box 6)
  - Personal Correspondence: S 1959-1962, 1977-1981, 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Personal Correspondence: T-Z 1959-1962, 1977-1981, 8 folders (Box 7)
  - Personal Correspondence: Waring, Tom 1959-1962 (Box 7)
  - Personal Correspondence: Miscellaneous 1962 (Box 7)
- Reader Mail
  - Abortion 1978-1982 (Box 8)
  - Agriculture 1978, 1983 (Box 8)
  - "Agronsky and Company" 1978-1984 (Box 8)
  - Airbags 1978, 1980 (Box 8)
  - Airlines 1978-1979 (Box 8)
  - Air Traffic Controllers 1981 (Box 8)
  - Alaska 1979 (Box 8)
  - Aliens 1981
  - American Legion 1979 (Box 8)
  - The American South: Towns and Cities 1982 (Box 8)
  - Anderson, John 1980 (Box 8)
  - Armed Forces 1979-1984 (Box 8)
  - Arms Limitation 1979 (Box 8)
  - Articles n.d. (Box 8)
  - Arts 1977-1981, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Assassinations 1979 (Box 9)
  - Auto Rates 1981 (Box 9)
  - AWACS 1981 (Box 9)
  - Awards 1978-1979 (Box 9)
  - Bagpipes 1983 (Box 9)
  - Banking 1983-1984 (Box 9)
  - Baseball 1983 (Box 9)
  - Birthday Piece 1981 (Box 9)
  - Black-Eyed Pea Society of America 1978, 1982 (Box 9)
  - Book of Common Prayer 1979 (Box 9)
  - Books 1978-1984, 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Boxing 1982-1983 (Box 9)
  - The Brethren 1979 (Box 9)
  - Broadcasting 1979-1981 (Box 10)
  - Brown, Jerry 1979 (Box 10)
  - Buckley, William F. 1982 (Box 10)
  - Budget 1980-1984 (Box 10)
  - Bureaucracy 1977, 6 folders (Box 10)
  - Bureaucracy 1979-1984, 7 folders (Box 11)
  - Business 1977-1984, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Campaign 1980 1979 (Box 12)
  - Campaign 1980: John Anderson 1980 (Box 12)
  - Carter, Jimmy 1978-1980, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Cats 1980-1981 (Box 12)
  - Censorship 1978-1984 (Box 12)
  - Central Intelligence Agency 1978-1979 (Box 12)
  - China 1978-1979 (Box 12)
  - Christmas Cards 1978-1979 (Box 12)
  - Chrysler Financial Problem 1979 (Box 12)
  - Cigarettes 1978-1979, 1982-1984 (Box 13)
  - Cities 1978 (Box 13)
  - Civil Service 1978 (Box 13)
  - Combs, Lou 1984 (Box 13)
  - Communism 1978-1984 (Box 13)
  - Computers 1983 (Box 13)
  - Congress 1978-1983 (Box 13)
  - Connally, John 1979 (Box 13)
  - Conservation 1978-1984, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Conservatism 1978-1984, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Constitution 1978-1984, 5 folders (Box 14)
  - Constitutional Amendments 1979 (Box 14)
  - Constitutional Bicentennial 1982-1983 (Box 14)
  - Consumerism 1978-1981 (Box 14)
  - Coogler, J. Gordon 1981 (Box 14)
  - Courts 1978-1984, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Crime 1978-1984, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Death Penalty 1979 (Box 15)
  - Declaration of Independence 1983-1984 (Box 15)
  - Defense 1979-1981 (Box 15)
  - Dirigibles 1979 (Box 1979)
  - Drugs 1978-1979 (Box 15)
  - Dusseldorf Rules 1979 (Box 15)
  - Ecology 1978 (Box 15)
  - Economy 1978-1984, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Education 1978-1980, 8 folders (Box 16)
  - Education 1981-1984, 4 folders (Box 17)
  - Elections 1978-1984 (Box 17)
  - Electoral Reform 1978 (Box 17)
  - Energy 1977-1979, 3 folders (Box 17)
  - Energy 1980-1981 (Box 18)
  - Environment 1978-1984 (Box 18)
  - Equal Rights Amendment 1978-1984, 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Ethics 1980 (Box 18)
  - Families 1980-1981 (Box 18)
  - Family Conference 1980 (Box 18)
  - Family - Kilpatrick 1978-1984 (Box 18)
  - Fan Mail 1978 (Box 18)
  - Fan Mail 1979-1984, 7 folders (Box 19)
  - Farming 1979 (Box 19)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation 1978 (Box 20)
  - Firearms 1979 (Box 20)
  - Flags 1979-1980 (Box 20)
  - Fluoridation 1978-1983 (Box 20)
  - Food 1979, 1983 (Box 20)
  - Ford, Gerald 1978, 1981 (Box 20)
  - Foreign Affairs 1977-1979, 5 folders (Box 20)
  - Foreign Affairs 1980-1984, 4 folders (Box 21)
  - The Foxes' Union 1980, 1982, 1984 (Box 21)
  - Funeral Industry 1978 (Box 21)
  - Gambling 1980-1981 (Box 21)
  - Gifted Child 1979 (Box 21)
  - Government 1978-1979 (Box 21)
  - Government Control 1979 (Box 21)
  - Gun Control 1978-1984 (Box 21)
  - Health Care 1978-1984, 8 folders (Box 22)
  - Heather 1980 (Box 22)
  - Heroism 1982 (Box 22)
  - Hinkley Verdict 1982 (Box 22)
  - Hiss, Alger 1978 (Box 22)
  - Horse Racing 1978 (Box 22)
  - Hotels 1978 (Box 22)
  - Housing 1978-1979 (Box 23)
  - Human Rights 1978 (Box 23)
  - Illegal Aliens 1978-1979 (Box 23)
  - Immigration 1983-1984 (Box 23)
  - Inflation 1978 (Box 23)
  - Invitations Regretted 1978 (Box 23)
  - Israeli Raid 1981 (Box 23)
  - Jefferson Foundation 1983 (Box 23)
  - Journalism 1978 (Box 23)
  - Junk Food 1979 (Box 23)
  - Kennedy, Teddy 1978-1979 (Box 23)
  - Kinsolving Affair 1978 (Box 23)
  - Know You 1979 (Box 23)
  - Labor 1976-1984, 4 folders (Box 23)
  - Laetrile 1978, 1980, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Laetrile 1981 (Box 24)
  - Language 1979 (Box 24)
  - Law 1978-1984, 5 folders (Box 24)
  - Legal Services 1978-1984, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Libraries 1978 (Box 24)
  - Lobbyists 1983 (Box 24)
  - Marijuana 1978 (Box 24)
  - Maritime Affairs 1979 (Box 24)
  - Media 1982-1984 (Box 25)
  - Mencken, H.L. 1978-1980 (Box 25)
  - Military 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - National Health Insurance 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - Nation's Business 1978 (Box 25)
  - Newspaper Speeches 1979 (Box 25)
  - Newspapers 1978-1984, 6 folders (Box 25)
  - Nixon, Richard 1978-1982 (Box 26)
  - No Fault Insurance 1978-1979 (Box 26)
  - Nuclear Arms 1979 (Box 26)
  - Nuclear Energy 1979 (Box 26)
  - Nuclear Power 1980-1984, 3 folders (Box 26)
  - Nut Mail 1977-1979, 3 folders (Box 26)
  - Obscenity 1978 (Box 27)
  - Occupational Safety and Health Administration 1978-1979 (Box 27)
  - Oklahoma 1978 (Box 27)
  - Panama Canal 1978-1979 (Box 27)
  - Pensions 1981 (Box 27)
  - Poetry 1978-1979 (Box 27)
  - A Political Bestiary 1978-1979 (Box 27)
  - Politics 1978-1979, 7 folders (Box 27)
  - Politics 1980-1984, 5 folders (Box 28)
  - Polls 1978-1979 (Box 28)
  - Population 1978-1984 (Box 28)
  - Pornography 1978-1978, 1984 (Box 28)
  - Postal Service 1978-1982, 2 folders (Box 29)
  - Presidential Election 1984 (Box 29)
  - Press 1978-1979 (Box 29)
  - Privacy 1978-1979 (Box 29)
  - Professional Air Traffic Controllers Organization 1982 (Box 29)
  - Propaganda 1979 (Box 29)
  - Prostitution 1981 (Box 29)
  - Public Braodcasting 1983 (Box 29)
  - Public Employee Unionism 1978 (Box 29)
  - Public Works 1980 (Box 29)
  - Race 1977-1978, 3 folders (Box 29)
  - Race 1979-1984, 4 folders (Box 30)
  - Randolph-Macon Academy 1979 (Box 30)
  - Reading 1978-1982 (Box 30)
  - Reagan, Ronald 1979-1984, 3 folders (Box 30)
  - Regrets 1978-1979 (Box 30)
  - Regulation 1978-1979 (Box 31)
  - Religion 1978-1984, 6 folders (Box 31)
  - Rhodesia 1979 (Box 31)
  - Right to Work 1978 (Box 31)
  - Robbery - Shared Experiences 1980 (Box 31)
  - Robbery - Sympathy 1980 (Box 31)
  - Rosebud - Skunk 1982, 5 folders (Box 32)
  - Rural Electric Act 1984 (Box 32)
  - Salaries 1981 (Box 32)
  - Satire 1978-1984 (Box 32)
  - Saturday Review 1979 (Box 32)
  - Science 1978 (Box 32)
  - Scottish Games 1978 (Box 32)
  - Scrabble 1978-1984, 9 folders (Box 33)
  - Scrabble Book 1977 (Box 34)
  - Secret Service 1982 (Box 34)
  - "Sixty Minutes" 1978-1979 (Box 34)
  - Smoking 1978 (Box 34)
  - Social Security 1978-1984, 3 folders (Box 34)
  - Socialism 1979 (Box 34)
  - Sodium Valproate 1978 (Box 34)
  - South 1983 (Box 34)
  - Space 1979 (Box 34)
  - Spelvin, Jay Toliver 1978 (Box 34)
  - Squeal Rule 1983 (Box 34)
  - Strategic Arms Limitations Talks II 1979 (Box 34)
  - Subscriptions 1978 (Box 34)
  - Supreme Court of the United States 1978-1984, 2 folders (Box 34)
  - Taxation 1977-1984, 7 folders (Box 35)
  - Teamsters 1981 (Box 35)
  - Television 1979-1984 (Box 35)
  - The Tennessee-Tombigbee Waterway 1980-1981 (Box 36)
  - Texas 1978 (Box 36)
  - Thank You Letters 1978-1979, 1984 (Box 36)
  - Trade 1983 (Box 36)
  - Transportation 1978-1984 (Box 36)
  - Travel 1980-1983 (Box 36)
  - Treasure 1978 (Box 36)
  - Treaties 1982 (Box 36)
  - Unions 1980, 1983 (Box 36)
  - United Nations 1978-1979 (Box 36)
  - Universal Press Syndicate 1984 (Box 36)
  - Veterans 1978-1979, 2 folders (Box 36)
  - Vietnam 1980-1982 (Box 36)
  - Vietnam Veterans 1981 (Box 36)
  - Volunteerism 1978 (Box 1978)
  - Voting Rights 1978, 1982-1983 (Box 36)
  - Watt, James 1983 (Box 36)
  - Welfare 1977-1982, 2 folders (Box 37)
  - Washington Star Syndicate Promotions 1978 (Box 37)
  - Writing 1978-1979, 6 folders (Box 37)
  - Writing 1979-1980, 1984, 2 folders (Box 38)
  - Yale University 1978 (Box 38)
  - Young, Andrew 1978 (Box 38)
- Radio & Television Transcripts
  - "Meet the Press" Transcripts 1977, 1979 (Box 38)
  - National Public Radio, "National Town Meeting" Transcript 16 Oct 1980 (Box 38)
  - "Open Mind" Correspondence 1962 (Box 38)
  - "Sixty Minutes" Transcripts 1977-1979 (Box 38)
  - "Spectrum" Commentaries and Related Material 1978, 2 folders (Box 38)
  - WDVM Post-Newsweek Commentaries 1979 (Box 38)
  - WDVM Post-Newsweek Commentaries 1980-1981 (Box 39)
  - WTOP Commentaries 1974-1975, 1977-1978, 4 folders (Box 39)
- Articles, Books & Related Material
  - The American South: Four Seasons of the Land(Original Manuscript) 1980 (Box 39)
  - The American South: Four Seasons of the Land(Final Manuscript) n.d. (Box 39)
  - The American South: Towns and Cities(Fourth Draft) 23 Feb 1982 (Box 39)
  - The American South: Towns and Cities(Complete Manuscript) 10 May 1982 (Box 39)
  - Arlington House Publishers 1967-1972 (Box 39)
  - Columns 1975-1977, 7 folders (Box 40)
  - Columns 1978-1979, 7 folders (Box 41)
  - Columns 1979 (Box 41)
  - "A Conservative View" Promotional Material 1965, 1976, 1977 (Box 42)
  - "Crisis in Confidence" Lecture 1974 (Box 42)
  - The Foxes' Union(Manuscript) 1977, 2 folders (Box 42)
  - The Foxes' Union(Revisions) Jun 1976 (Box 42)
  - The Foxes' Union(Final Manuscript) n.d., 2 folders (Box 42)
  - The Foxes' Union (General Correspondence) Aug-Dec 1977, 2 folders (Box 42)
  - The Foxes' Union(General Correspondence) Jan 1978-Jun 1979, n.d., 7 folders (Box 43)
  - Harper's Magazine Article, "A Conservative Prophecy" 1965 (Box 43)
  - "Harvest Time is the Best Time," in Southern Living1981 (Box 43)
  - A Political Bestiary(Miscellaneous Notes) 1976-1978, 2 folders (Box 44)
  - A Political Bestiary(Final Draft) n.d. (Box 44)
  - A Political Bestiary(Gatherings) 1978 (Box 44)
  - A Political Bestiary(First Set of Editor's Corrections, Dust Jacket and Drawings) 1 May 1978 (Box 44)
  - A Political Bestiary(Second Set of Editor's Corrections and Drawings) 23 May 1978 (Box 44)
  - A Political Bestiary(Page Proofs) n.d. (Box 44)
  - A Political Bestiary (Setting Copy) n.d. (Box 44)
  - A Political Bestiary(Advance Proof) Oct 1978 (Box 44)
  - A Political Bestiary(General Correspondence) 1977, 1978, 1980 (Box 44)
  - A Political Bestiary(Correspondence with Eugene McCarthy) 1976, 1978 (Box 44)
  - A Political Bestiary(Promotional Material) 1978-1979 (Box 45)
  - A Political Bestiary(Reviews) 1978-1979 (Box 45)
  - Reagan, Nancy: Biography for Inaugural Book Nov-Dec 1980 (Box 45)
  - Washington Star Syndicate: Correspondence 1978-1979 (Box 45)
  - Washington Star Syndicate: Promotional Material 1965-1967, 1970, 1976-1977, 1979, 2 folders (Box 45)
  - Washington Star Syndicate: Reprint Permission 1978-1979 (Box 45)
  - Washington Star Syndicate: Statements accompanied by Kilpatrick Client Lists 1965-1975, 2 folders (Box 45)
  - "What's Wrong with the Ediorial Page?" in the American Society of Newspapers Editors BulletinMay 1983 (Box 45)
- Miscellaneous Material
  - Calendars, with Kilpatrick Appointments 1976-1978 (Box 46)
  - Carter, Jimmy: Campaign Material 1974-1976 (Box 46)
  - Carter, Jimmy: Campaign Promises 1976-1977 (Box 46)
  - Carter, Jimmy: Critical Stuff 1976 (Box 46)
  - Carter, Jimmy: Family and Associates 1976-1977 (Box 46)
  - Carter, Jimmy: General 1978-1980 (Box 46)
  - Carter, Jimmy: Religion 1976 (Box 46)
  - Carter, Jimmy: Transition Fund 1977 (Box 46)
  - Kilpatrick, James J.: Publicity 1964-1977 (Box 46)
  - National Women's Conference 1977 (Box 46)
  - Photographs 1959-1982, n.d. (Box 46)
  - Presidential Campaign, 1976: Birch Bayh 1975-1976 (Box 47)
  - Presidential Campaign, 1976: Jimmy Carter 1975-1976 (Box 47)
  - Presidential Campaign, 1976: Democratic Convention 1976 (Box 47)
  - Presidential Campaign, 1976: Henry Jackson 1975-1976 (Box 47)
  - Presidential Campaign, 1976: Libertarians 1972-1976 (Box 47)
  - Presidential Campaign, 1976: Eugene McCarthy 1974-1976 (Box 47)
  - Presidential Campaign, 1976: Primaries May 1976 (Box 47)
  - Presidenial Campaign, 1976: Republican Convention Aug 1976 (Box 47)
  - Presidential Campaign, 1976: Speech Notes 1972, 1975, 1976 (Box 47)
  - Presidential Campaign, 1976: Third Parties 1976 (Box 47)
  - Shackman Libel Suit 1968-1969 (Box 48)
  - Speech Notes: Miscellaneous 1979 (Box 48)
  - Trip Notes: England Feb-Apr 1971 (Box 48)
  - Trip Notes: Europe Sep-Nov 1974 (Box 48)
  - Trip Notes: Italy Aug-Dec 1964 (Box 48)
  - Trip Notes: Portugal Apr 1971 (Box 48)
  - Trip Notes: Russia May 1961 (Box 48)
  - Trip Notes: South Africa Aug-Sep 1971 (Box 48)
  - Trip Notes: Spain Mar 1971 (Box 48)
  - Trip Notes: Venezuela Dec 1967-Feb 1968 (Box 48)
- Videocassette & Tape Recordings
  - Videocassette Recording Nov 1982, 30 minutes
    "Vietnam War Memorial" in Watch On Washington TV Series, Produced by John Hamilton of Hamilton Productions, Inc., with James J. Kilpatrick, John Hamilton, Nancy Bradsher, and Robert Cohen
  - Tape Recordings of "Agronsky and Company"
    - 1. Libyan Crisis/Hit Teams 12 Dec 1981 (Box 49)
    - 2. Martial Law in Poland 19 Dec 1981 (Box 49)
    - 3. Response of Reagan to Polish Crisis/"Death" of the ERA 26 Dec 1981 (Box 49)
    - 4. Reflections on the Year Past & Present 2 Jan 1982 (Box 49)
    - 5. Reagan's Economic Policy/Texas Senatorial Election 8 Jan 1982 (Box 49)
    - 6. Reagan's Reappraisal of Policy/Unemployment 9 Jan 1982 (Box 49)
    - 7. Recession/United Nations sanctions re Polish Crisis 16 Jan 1982 (Box 49)
    - 8. FDR 100 Year Anniversary/Reagan Press Conference 23 Jan 1982 (Box 49)
    - 9. New Federalism/U.S. Aid for the Junta in El Salvador/Admiral Rickover 30 Jan 1982 (Box 49)
    - 10. Reaganomics & New Federalism/Busing/Kennedy Tapes 6 Feb 1982 (Box 49)
    - 11. Reagan's Budget and the Deficit 12 Feb 1982 (Box 49)
    - 12. Reagan's Press Conference/Combat Troops in El Salvador 20 Feb 1982 (Box 49)
    - 13. Caribbean Basin Policy/Israeli Security 27 Feb 1982 (Box 49)
    - 14. Sen. Williams Affair/Congress & Big Business re Economic Policy/Caribbean Policy 6 Mar 1982 (Box 49)
    - 15. Mexican Plan re Nicaragua & El Salvador/Nuclear Arsenal Reeeze/Williams Resigns 13 Mar 1982 (Box 49)
    - 16. Media & Big Business re Economic Policy/Nuclear Weapons Freeze/Central America & Middle East Crises 20 Mar 1982 (Box 49)
    - 17. Congress re Reagan Budget/The Poor/Central America 27 Mar 1982 (Box 49)
    - 18. Debate Over Reagan Comments 3 Apr 1982 (Box 49)
    - 19. Falkland Crisis/Budget Compromise/First Use Issue 10 Apr 1982 (Box 49)
    - 20. Falkland Crisis/Middle East/ Budget Conflict of Congress & Reagan 17 Apr 1982 (Box 49)
    - 21. Budget Compromise/Falkland Crisis/Israel & Egypt/Tax-Exemption for Private Schools 24 Apr 1982 (Box 49)
    - 22. Falkland Crisis/Budget Compromise 1 May 1982 (Box 49)
    - 23. "Second Battle of the Budget/Voluntary Prayer in Public Schools 8 May 1982 (Box 49)
    - 24. Nuclear Weapons Reductions/The Budget/Brantiff Airlines 15 May 1982 (Box 49)
    - 25. Falkland Islands/Reagan's Attorney General Meese/Negotiations re Nuclear Weapons/Kennedy's Assassination 22 May 1982 (Box 49)
    - 26. House of Rep. re Budget/Falkland Islands/Reagan Support 29 May 1982 (Box 49)
    - 27. American Economic Recovery/Unemployment/Falkland Islands/Protracted Nuclear War 5 Jun 1982 (Box 49)
    - 28. Lebanese Crisis/President's European Trip/Falkland Islands 12 Jun 1982 (Box 49)
    - 29. Reagan re Soviet/Lebanese Crisis/Falkland War/Voting Rights Act 19 Jun 1982 (Box 49)
    - 30. Lebanese Crisis/Hinckley Verdict/Presidential Immunity/Housing Bill 26 Jun 1982 (Box 49)
    - 31. Unemployment/Lebanese Crisis/Will Reagan Run Again? 3 Jul 1982, Note: tape is damaged at the beginning; do not rewind past the introductory music (Box 49)
    - 32. Lebanese Crisis/Tax Proposals/Supreme Court 9 Jul 1982 (Box 49)
    - 33. Lebanon/Iran-Iraq War/Economy/Balanced Budget Amendment/Shultz 17 Jul 1982 (Box 49)
    - 34. Senate re Taxes/Economic News/Siberian Gas Pipeline 24 Jul 1982 (Box 49)
    - 35. Reagan re Economics/Lebanese Crisis - the Arab Plan/James Watt 31 Jul 1982 (Box 49)
    - 36. Unemployment/Beirut/Nuclear Freeze 7 Aug 1982 (Box 49)
    - 37. Soviet Leadership/Gas Tax/Congressional Job Programs/Vietnam Tribute 13 Aug 1982 (Box 49)
    - 38. Lebanese Crisis-Begin/Tax Bill/Reagan Policy 14 Aug 1982 (Box 49)
    - 39. Tax Increase Bill/Lebanon & West Beirut 21 Aug 1982 (Box 49)
    - 40. Stock Market/Siberian Gas Pipeline/Draft Registration/Pro-Football Players 28 Aug 1982 (Box 49)
    - 41. Middle East Peace Plan/Supplemental Appropriation Bill/Unemployment/Farm Income 4 Sep 1982 (Box 49)
    - 42. President and Congress/Middle East Peace Plan 11 Sep 1982 (Box 49)
    - 43. Special Congressional Session/Israel and Lebanon/Abortion - Jessie Helms 18 Sep 1982 (Box 49)
    - 44. Middle East Crisis/School Prayer/Reagan Inflation/NFL 25 Sep 1982 (Box 49)
    - 45. Democrats and Reagan/Beirut and the Marines/West Germany/NFL Strike 2 Oct 1982 (Box 49)
    - 46. State of the Economy/Nuclear Freeze 9 Oct 1982 (Box 49)
    - 47. Economic Policy/Israel and Lebanon/Civil Rights Case 16 Oct 1982 (Box 49)
    - 48. "Stay the Course" Slogan/The Soviet Union/Arabs and the Middle East Peace 23 Oct 1982 (Box 49)
    - 49. Upcoming Congressional Election/Arms Race 30 Oct 1982 (Box 50)
    - 50. Elections/Unemployment 6 Nov 1982 (Box 50)
    - 51. Detente/Tax Cuts 20 Nov 1982 (Box 50)
    - 52. Unemployment/Tax & Missile Policies/Begin Government/Egypt 27 Nov 1982 (Box 50)
    - 53. Ted Kennedy/Mechanical Hearts/Economic Worries 4 Dec 1982 (Box 50)
    - 54. MX Missile/Democratic Job Programs/Execution by Injection 11 Dec 1982 (Box 50)
    - 55. Lame Duck Congress/Job Bills/Legal Services Corp./Reverse Discrimination/Plot to Kill the Pope 18 Dec 1982 (Box 50)
    - 57. Reflections on the Year Past & Present 30 Dec 1982 (Box 50)
    - 58. Howard Baker/Harris Poll/Tax Increases/U.S. Arms Control Leadership 15 Jan 1983 (Box 50)
    - 59. Reagan's Future Outlook/Federal Budget/Japanese Prime Minister 22 Jan 1983 (Box 50)
    - 60. Economic Recovery/State of the Union Address/Europe and Disarmament 29 Jan 1983 (Box 60)
    - 61. Unemployment/Congressional Debates/Arms Control Leader/Presidental Candidates for 1984 5 Feb 1983 (Box 50)
    - 62. Israeli Policy/Recession Aid/Oxford Union/ The Winds of War12 Feb 1983 (Box 50)
    - 63. President & Congress/Libyan Crisis/Israeli Policy 19 Feb 1983 (Box 50)
    - 64. Black Congressman for Mayor/Arms Control Agency/Teenage Sex 26 Feb 1983 (Box 50)
    - 65. El Salvador/The Economy/Health & Human Services 5 Mar 1983 (Box 50)
    - 66. El Salvador/Resignation of EPA Director/Jobs Bill/Reporters 12 Mar 1983 (Box 50)
    - 67. Jobs Bill/Budget Proposal/Arms Control Agency/Nuclear Freeze Resolution/Rape Case/Soviet Union 19 Mar 1983 (Box 50)
    - 68. Anti-Missile Defense System/Budget Resolution/Aid to El Salvador/The EPA 26 Mar 1983 (Box 50)
    - 69. Arms Control/F-16 Planes for Israel/Nicaragua/Chicago Mayorial Campaign 2 Apr 1983 (Box 50)
    - 70. Congress/Chinese/James Watt 9 Apr 1983 (Box 50)
    - 71. Nicaragua/Kenneth Edleman/Black Political Power 16 Apr 1983 (Box 50)
    - 72. Congress/MX Missiles/Presidental Candidates 23 Apr 1983 (Box 50)
    - 73. Central American Policy/Commission on Education/ Lebanon and the Middle East 30 Apr 1983 (Box 50)
    - 74. Role of American Mothers/Pastoral Letter Re Arms Control/CBS Memoranda re Documentary 7 May 1983 (Box 50)
    - 75. MX Missile Plan/Economic Policy/Syrians and Lebanon 14 May 1983 (Box 50)
    - 76. Budget/Syria and Lebanon/Air Traffic Control/Presidental Candidates 21 May 1983 (Box 50)
    - 77. MX Missile Funds/Honduras/Meeting of Industrial Democracies/Supreme Court Decisions 28 May 1983 (Box 50)
    - 78. Central American Policy/Andropov/Summit at Williamsburg 4 Jun 1983 (Box 50)
    - 79. Margaret Thatcher/Arms Control Policy/Ceiling on Outside Lecture Income 11 Jun 1983 (Box 50)
    - 80. Abortion/U.S.-Soviet Relations/Senate Pay Raise 18 Jun 1983 (Box 50)
    - 81. Supreme Court & Legislative Veto/Defiance of Congress re Reagan's Budget/Pope in Poland 25 Jun 1983 (Box 50)
    - 82. Case of the Purloined Carter Papers/Tax Cut/Tax Breaks for Private School Children 2 Jul 1983 (Box 50)
    - 83. Supreme Court re Equal Benefits for Men & Women/Lebanese Troop Withdrawal/George Will & the Briefing of Reagan 9 Jul 1983 (Box 50)
    - 84. Presidental Politics/U.S. Involvement in Central America/Illicit Sex in the House of Representatives 16 Jul 1983 (Box 50)
    - 85. Central America/State of the Economy/House Censure of 2 Members/MX Missile 23 Jul 1983 (Box 50)
    - 86. Role of U.S.S.R. in Central America/Grain Sale to U.S.S.R./Jesse Jackson & Black Voters 30 Jul 1983 (Box 50)
    - 87. Central American Crisis Cools Off/Congress & Unfinished Business/15% of Americans on or Below Poverty Line/Kilpatrick Out with Triple Bypass Heart Surgery 6 Aug 1983 (Box 50)
    - 88. U.S. - Mexican Summit/War Games/Libyan War with Chad a French Problem 13 Aug 1983 (Box 50)